James Hagen

Hagenjh@gmail.com (303) 808-6603 Colorado Springs, CO

UX Designer

GitHub: github.com/Hagendazzj LinkedIn: linkedin.com/hagenjh Portfolio: dribbble.com/hagenjh

Summary

A strong creative expert with over 7 years of experience in art direction, and customer experience. Focused on designing with a "humans first" perspective.

Skills

Tools: Figma, Adobe XD, InVision, GitHub

Languages: HTML, CSS

Methods: User research, Competitive analysis, User stories, User personas, User testing, UX design, UI design, Visual design

Branding, Prototyping, Mock-ups

Recent Projects

BusyBus | https://hagendazzj.github.io/ChallengeFF/

- Deployed and analyzed survey information to craft user stories, visual design and create a coded mockup
- Tech: HTML, CSS and Figma

Dotlets | shorturl.at/ampuT

- Assessed user research, found a specific market and build hi-fi prototypes to solve the problem
- Tech: Google forms and Figma

Experience

Freelance Web Designer, Self Employed

Colorado Springs, CO

- Developed innovative, user-friendly websites
- Advised in expert marketing practices for client success
- Created Logo design and identity brand strategy for customers

Marketing Consultant - Sales, Outreach

July 2017 - October 2018

November 2018 - May 2019

Colorado Springs, CO

- Used wireframing and research when advising the internal team on new CRM creation
- Consulted in growth-driven marketing and branding techniques
- Developed launch strategies crafted to each organization's needs

Specialist, Apple

November 2013 - April 2017

San Diego, CA

- Demonstrated innovation by creating a winning presentation, educating teams about merchandising
- Launched a successful education campaign that resulted in a 19% increase in new iPhone financing
- Increased touchpoints by 60% with corporate merchandising team

Education

Bloc

UX Design Apprentice

July 2019 - Present

- Learned industry best practices and design process standards with a focus
- on UX Research, Visual Design, and Front-end development.
- Created and deployed projects while learning new tools and frameworks by
- collaborating several hours every week with a senior product designer.

New Life Church School of Worship 2008-2009